Guilherme Patriota

Electric Engineer



H4V 2Y2 Montréal/QC



+1 (438) 926-0872



linkedin.com/in/guilhermepatriota



gdp.ai.data.eng@gmail.com

About me –

Guilherme Patriota is a fast learner professional who works as IT/Data Science/AI Professor and Electrical Engineer with a Masters in Electrical Engineering with AI applyed telecommunications in search of an opportunity to work in his areas of interest. Working as a University Professor in the Software Engineering and Data Science courses at UNINTER - International University Center, in Brasil, since 2021 and as Professor in other universities since 2016.

Skills ——

Teamwork, Leadership, Analytical Mind

Eletronics, IoT, MQTT, Kafka

Logic, Linux, Docker

C++, R, Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, AI

3D Modeling, 3D Printing, Teaching

DBA, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, AWS, RDS

Hbase, Redis, MongoDB, Elasticsearch

Java, JavaScript, REST API, DJANGO

Big Data, Hadoop, Spark, Scala

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness)

Portfolio ———



High technologies; Data Analysis; Data Science; Big Data; Teaching; AI; Blockchains; New Technologies; 3D Print; Research; Databases; Python; Agile Development; Data structures; Software Architectures; **Design Patterns**

Education

2021-2022 Postgraduate Course in

Teacher Training for E-Learning

UNINTER/Brazil This postgraduate course covered a range of topics related to online pedagogy, including the use of flipped classroom techniques, use of learning management systems (LMS) and other popular distance

learning techniques.

2013-2016 MBA in Healthcare

Improuvments into medical equipments maintenance, team leader-

FGV/Brazil

Book

32h

8h

8h

9 weeks

ship and healthcare services management.

M.Sc. Electrical Engineer 2009-2011 UFPR/Brazil

> AI applyed to electronics and telecommunications focused on development of a new outdoor propagation model for radio waves and GSM

(3G, 4G and 5G signals - ISBN-13 9783639830842 (EAN).

2002-2006 B.Sc. Electrical Engineer UFPR/Brazil Bachelor degree in electronics and telecommunications.

2004-2004 B.Sc. Electrical Engineer **ENSPS/France**

Sandwitch bachelor degree in Electrical Engineer - Electronics

Publications

2020

2020

2020

2020

2021 Modelo de propagação outdoor para região

urbana densa em Curitiba.

Outdoor propagation model for dense urban region in Curitiba.

Published by Novas Edicoes Academicas

ISBN-13: 9783639830842 (EAN)

Complementary Studies

2020	Knowledge discovery	in database and datamining.	60h
------	---------------------	-----------------------------	-----

UFPR/Brazil

Aldeia Coworking/Brazil

Introduction to computer programming using python.

Data Science foundations.

MITx

AI fundamentals. Data Science Academy

Data Science Academy

Datascience 2.0.

Guilherme Patriota

Electric Engineer



H4V 2Y2 Montréal/QC



+1 (438) 926-0872



linkedin.com/in/guilhermepatriota



gdp.ai.data.eng@gmail.com

About me —

Guilherme Patriota is a fast learner professional who works as IT/Data Science/AI Professor and Electrical Engineer with a Masters in Electrical Engineering with AI applyed telecommunications in search of an opportunity to work in his areas of interest. Working as a University Professor in the Software Engineering and Data Science courses at UNINTER - International University Center, in Brasil, since 2021 and as Professor in other universities since 2016.

Skills ———

Teamwork, Leadership, Analytical Mind

Eletronics, IoT, MQTT, Kafka

Logic, Linux, Docker

C++, R, Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, AI

3D Modeling, 3D Printing, Teaching

DBA, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, AWS, RDS

Hbase, Redis, MongoDB, Elasticsearch

Java, JavaScript, REST API, DJANGO

Big Data, Hadoop, Spark, Scala

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness)

Portfolio ———



Experience

since 2016 University Professor

FAFSP and UNINTER

University Professor in the Software Engineering, Computer Engineering and Data Science courses at UNINTER - International University Center in Brasil. Subjects: Systems analysis and development, Big Data, Natural Language Processing, NoSQL database, Embedded Systems, Artificial intelligence, electronics, C programming language, Python, Electromagnetism, Medical imaging, Maintenance of biomedical systems

2020-2021 New Technologies Developer

Boa Impressão 3D

Develop eletronics and software for new 3d printers and other products. Manage the assembly line.

2018-2020 3D Printer Technician.

Build, repair and configure 3d printer and make and print 3d modeling spare parts for medical equipments and research on healthcare projects.

2017-2018 Medical Equipments Engineer

Santa Casa Hospital

Maintain and repair medical equipments and manage technician teams, building maintenance team manager and technical responsi-

ble for new medical equipment purchasing.

2015-2017 Medical Equipments Engineer Curitiba's Red Cross Hospital

Maintain and repair medical equipments, manage technician teams, creation and manage of PMO (PMBOK Office) for internal projects like new rooms for equipments and maintenance of building structure.

Building maintenance team manager.

2012-2014 Medical Equipments Engineer Vitoria Hospital/Unitedhealth Amil

Maintain and repair medical equipments and manage technician teams and technical responsible for new medical equipment purchas-

Volunteer Experience

2020 Volunteer

Development, 3D printing and delivery of 500 face shields for donation to healthcare professionals in Curitiba during the first 6 months of the

COVID-19 pandemic in Brazil.

2009-2010 Brazilian Scouts Monitor GEUJ - Grupo Escoteiro União Juventus

> Organize activities for Pionneers (young people between 15 and 17 years old) assisting them in developing their physical, spiritual, intel-

lectual, social and affective potential.

Other information

Disponibility

OWP until November 2023. Part or full time.

Languages

English, French and Portuguese.

Social

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/guilhermepatriota